Guide to the Reverend John Minter's research materials about the youth movement in Berkeley, California, 1969-1973 MS 306
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Reverend John Minter's research materials about the youth movement in Berkeley, California
1969-1973
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Minter, John
MS 306
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
This collection contains notes and printed material largely related to John Minter's study of the youth movement in the Berkeley, California area, including the resulting publication by Minter titled "Youth Alive." A great deal of the printed ephemera reflects the young adult "counter culture" of the late 1960's and early 1970's. Also included is some additional material on Christian movements in the Houston area.
Biographical Note
John Minter served as pastor of the University Presbyterian Church in Houston and researched the youth movement in the Berkeley, California area in the 1960s and 1970s.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains notes and printed material largely related to Minter's study of the youth movement in the Berkeley, California area, including the resulting publication by Minter titled Youth Alive (folder 1). Also included is some additional material on Christian movements in the Houston area related to Minter's position as pastor of the University Presbyterian Church in Houston. A great deal of the printed ephemera reflects the young adult "counter culture" of the late 1960s and early 1970s.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift donated by John Minter on August 18, 1980.
Index Terms
Subjects
Religion; Social life and customs
Document Types
articles
- Series I: Publications, 46525
  - Youth Alive by John Minter – "a Paper submitted to the Danforth Foundation based on an Underwood Fellowship study at the Wright Institute and the San Francisco Bay Area in the Fall of 1970.", 46542 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes, correspondence, and lists of addresses, ca. 1970, 46541 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Peace Brigade (Berkeley); publications and notes regarding the Brigade - ca. 1970-1973, 46540 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lama Foundation (San Cristobal, New Mexico); publications - 1970, 46539 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Christian World Liberation Front (Berkeley); publications, miscellaneous related publications, note - 1970, 46538 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Human Abilities (Oakland, California); publications, notes on the Institute and the "Morehouse Commune", Presbyterian Church pamphlet - 1970, 46537 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Berkeley Free Church and Submarine Church Press (Berkeley); publications - 1969-1970, 46536 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Briarparch House Church (Berkeley); publications and related articles - 1969-1970, 46535 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hare Krishna (Boston, etc.); publications and notes - 1970-1973, 46534 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - One World Family (Berkeley); publications and notes - 1970, 46533 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Texas Soul Clinic (Mingus, Texas); publications - 1970, 46532 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous publications – Berkeley area, part I - no date; 1970-1971, 46531 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous publications – Berkeley area, part II - 1972-1973, 46530 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous publications – Houston area, part I - 1969-1971, 46529 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous publications – Houston area, part II - 1972-1973, 46528 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous publications – general, part I - 1970-1973, 46527 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous publications – general, part II - 1970-1973, 46526 (Box 1, Folder 17)